Aimee Knight

Full Stack Engineer/Channel Lead

170 Plum Nelly Circle
Brentwood, TN 37027
(205) 913-4533
AimeeMarieKnight@gmail.com
AimeeMarieKnight.com

I'm passionately curious about emerging technology, while consistently focused on fundamental principles. As a former professional figure skater, I'm extremely driven, holding myself and the software I write to the highest standards. I enjoy staying active in the JavaScript community through speaking at conferences, podcasting, blogging at AimeeMarieKnight.com and helping to organize meetups and conferences.

While much of the code I write for my employer is private, my open source software projects can be found on <u>GitHub</u>.

Current Summary

Warner Bros Digital Labs (NYC, NY/Remote)

Front End Software Engineer/Channel Lead, 2016-Present

As a Front End Software Engineer and Channel Lead at Warner Bros Digital Labs, I've worked in a rapidly paced environment building out features for <u>Boomerang</u>, <u>Warner Archive</u>, <u>Moodica</u>, and <u>DramaFever</u> using Angular.js and Django. While at Warner Bros, I have been especially focused on preparing our code base for the latest version of Angular by following a component model, and driving adoption of the latest version of JavaScript by leading weekly internal training sessions.

Strengths include:

- Test-driven development
- Designing/Writing Front End UI's with Angular.js and React.js
- Designing/Writing APIs with Node.js
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies and libraries
- Mentoring
- CSS

JavaScript Jabber & Angular Air

Panelist, 2015-Present

• Interview community leaders about various open source projects, and other popular JavaScript and Angular topics.

Experience

Kuali (Lehi, UT/Remote)

Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2016

- Built out features for a higher education curriculum management system using React.js, Redux, and Node.js with Express and Koa.
- Increasing product reliability and stability by helping to drive adoption of front end test with Enzyme and increasing back end test coverage.
- Helped implement the latest technologies within the code base including WebPack, Flow, JavaScript 2015 and JavaScript 2016.

Message Systems (Columbia, MD)

Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2014-2016

- Built out features for the core on-premise solution, and cloud offering, <u>SparkPost</u> utilizing Angular.js and Node.js.
- Led migration to ES6 and the official AngularJS style guide.
- Prepared UI for Angular 2.
- Maintained 100% front end and back end test coverage.

Nashville Software School (Nashville, TN)

Apprentice - Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015

Completed a six-month intensive, full-time, hands-on, fast-moving and rigorous study of software engineering. Emphasis was placed on building database driven applications, and working with other students while immersed in new and challenging material.

Highlights include: - Computer Science fundamentals, algorithms, operating systems and security - Test-driven development with Rspec & Mocha - Ruby * Ruby on Rails with SQLite and PostgreSQL - JavaScript & Node.js with MongoDB - Agile software development & pair-programming

Boost by Design LLC. (Richmond Hill, GA)

Junior Web Developer, 2013-2014

- Implement theme modifications for cross-browser support from completed Photoshop design files while maintaining W3C compliance.
- Utilize a mobile first design approach, implementing media queries for all standard breakpoints.
- Address issues with broken themes as well as hosting account configuration.
- Educate clients on Wordpress CMS, SEO, and accessibility best practices.
- Work within tight deadlines to satisfy urgent client requests.

Fast Forward Video Inc. (Irvine, CA)

Sales and Marketing Administrator, 2012

• Manage global customer base including and serve as primary Salesforce (CRM) administrator.

Restore Therapy Services Ltd. & Comfort Care Home Health and Hospice LLC. (Birmingham, AL)

Business Development Coordinator, 2009-2010

- Responsible for overseeing production Web Sites, SEO, and additional marketing material.
- Work with prospects, CEO and Director of Business Development to implement new contracts.

FitzMartin Inc. (Birmingham, AL)

Project Manager/Junior Account Manager, 2007-2009

- Collaborate with Software Developers, Creatives, and Account Executives to ensure projects deadlines are met on time and on budget.
- Set up production schedules for all projects in order to maintain critical path management for an average of 110 jobs per week.

City of Pelham - Pelham Civic Complex (Pelham, AL)

Private Figure Skating Coach, 2000-2007

• Instruct all ages and all levels in various disciplines of Figure Skating.

Education

- Nashville Software School Student / Apprentice Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015
- University of Massachusetts at Lowell Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, 2012-Present
- University of Alabama at Birmingham Summa Cum Laude Bachelor of Arts in Communication Management & Mass Communications, 2002-2007

Skills

- HTML5, Jade & Haml
- CSS3, Less & Sass
- Javascript (Including ES6) & jQuery
- Angular.js, React.js & Redux
- Ruby/Rails with Rspec
- Django
- Node.js/Express.js with Mocha
- Protractor & Selenium
- SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RethinkDB, ElasticSearch
- Grunt & Gulp
- Vim
- Git
- Amazon Web Services
- TravisCl, Coveralls, & Gemnasium
- Wordpress Theme Development
- Basic Adobe Photoshop and InDesign

References

References are available upon request.